aircraftspruce.com 2019-08-23

# Terms & Conditions | Aircraft Spruce

## SHIPPING AND DELIVERY

#### Same Day Shipping by 4pm & Delivery Date Estimate

Aircraft Spruce provides same day shipment of in stock items if the order is received prior to 4 pm local time at the origin warehouse of the shipment using the carrier UPS. Orders placed with carrier USPS, FedEx or other carriers are not covered in the 4 pm same day shipping policy. For online orders, items in the Shopping Cart will display stock status as well as an expected delivery day based on the shipping method chosen when "Default"ï¿½ origin is used. This date will factor the time the order is placed as well as origin warehouse and destination zip code. Carrier delays due to weather and other factors outside of our control removes Aircraft Spruce responsibility from quoted delivery date. Delivery dates will depend on exact time of order placement, so the true expected date will be referenced on the Order Confirmation screen. On Backordered items, Out of Stock items, Special Orders, Dropship items, and Non-stocking Products, we will provide an expected ship date if the item is on order from the supplier. However, these dates are expected delivery date of PO's and we cannot guarantee the items will be delivered within that window as factory delays and other elements outside of our control can delay the order. 

#### Ship and Backorder

Orders shipping within the lower 48 USA and within Alaska are defaulted to ship and backorder. If you would like your order held and shipped in one package, please note in the Special Instructions box that you would like the order to 'Ship Complete'. If you have a preferred ship date other than the date of order placement, please note that in the Special Instructions as well. International and Canadian orders are defaulted to Ship Complete when all items are in stock. The customer can select the "Ship and Backorder" option is in the Shopping Cart (Customer will be charged freight on both shipments). Special instructions or credit card declines may delay fulfillment of the order.

#### Shipping Charges

Shipping charges provided online are calculated from the weights and dimensions of the box(es) required to ship all the items on the order. The system will look for the optimal fulfillment logic to distribute the items to the required warehouse(s). Shipping rates quoted online will be applied to the order at invoicing. The exception to this is the Ship and Backorder option for International shipments in which case an estimate is provided and actual shipping charge will be calculated at time of invoicing each shipment. If the shipping charges seem incorrect for the items on the order, please use the Special Instructions box in the Shopping Cart to request a manual freight quote from a member of our staff. We will evaluate the contents of the order, origin warehouse(es), and destination and provide via email a new shipping quote. Please keep in mind that the order will be held until you confirm the new shipping estimate provided by the staff member. 

Shipping costs for certain product mixes or types cannot be calculated online. Examples of these types of products are wood, metal, oversized items, made to order items and other specialty cut materials. When this is the case, the shipping costs will be calculated at the invoicing station. The shipping costs charged will be based on the exact weights and dimensions of the actual box(es) used to ship the order. This condition will be referenced in the shopping cart by a note that says 'We are unable to accurately estimate the shipping costs of your order. Shipping Costs will be Calculated at Time of Shipping'. If you would like a manual estimate before the order ships, please use the Special Instructions box in the Shopping Cart to request a manual freight quote from a member of our staff. We will evaluate the contents of the order, origin warehouse(es), and destination and provide via email a new shipping quote. Please keep in mind that the order will be held until you confirm the new shipping estimate provided by the staff member.

Some oversize charges which were not able to be predicted online will be assessed at time of shipment. Packages over 48 inches in length will be assessed an additional handling fee as declared in the carrier's service guide. All packages will be charged at the greater of actual or dimensional weight. Pursuant to the carrier service guide, packages over 96 inches in length or 130 inches length and girth will also be assessed a fee for exceeding the maximum package size, in addition to being billed at a 90lb oversize rate. Dimensional weight is calculated as the total cubic inches of a package divided by a dimensional weight factor (domestic US is 194, outside US is 166). Some oversized items can be cut for shipping. If you think this might apply, please return to your shopping cart and include cutting instructions in the Special Instructions box.

Hazardous items may be assessed an additional hazardous shipping charge for each package containing hazardous materials. This fee, if it applies, will be added to the calculated freight charge. Shipping charges for phone in sales are calculated at the time of shipping based on the weights and dimensions of the box(es) used to ship the order. If you would like an estimate, just ask your friendly Aircraft Spruce sales agent and they will provide you one. 

#### Free Shipping on Orders Over $350 / $195 

Most orders over $350 in merchandise value, shipping within the 48 contiguous United States and within Alaska, will be shipped prepaid, with Aircraft Spruce paying the shipping cost. If your order qualifies for free shipping, it will be offered as a shipping method in the Shopping Cart. 'Free Ground' must be selected as the shipping method for the order to ship prepaid. Any other shipping selection will bill the quoted amount at the time of invoicing. Please inquire at the time of order if you have questions regarding the free shipping policy as it applies to your order. Normally, Free Shipping orders will be shipped via UPS, although if it is more economical, a different service like USPS may be used. Orders shipping by Fedex Ground do not qualify for prepaid shipping. Prepaid shipping is offered on battery and tire orders (some exceptions apply). For our dealer and wholesale customers, free shipping is offered for orders over $195. The same rules in the above section apply to the dealer free shipping policy. Free shipping must be requested at the time of order with your sales person on phone in orders. To qualify for free shipping in Alaska, the order must ship from our local Alaska branch in Wasilla to qualify.

#### Free Truck Freight on Orders over $5000

Aircraft Spruce will offer free freight on truck orders over $5,000. This is for all truck orders shipped to the 48 lower states. The order will have to ship from the warehouse closest to the customer. We will hold the order until we can ship complete from the closest warehouse to customer. If a customer wants us to ship and backorder, we will pay the freight on the first shipment by truck, but the customer will be responsible for the freight on the backordered items. 55 gallon drums and engine cylinders are excluded from free truck freight offer.

#### Free Shipping Exclusions

Orders that contain 5 gallon containers, engine cylinders, oversized items, specially cut materials (ie wood, metal, foam, rolled fabric, etc), packages measuring more than 84 inches length and girth or 48 inches long or exceed 100 pounds total weight are excluded from this promotion. Special order or made to order items may be excluded from the shipping promotion. Core charges, hazardous materials fees, box charges, and insurance are not considered part of the order minimum for free shipping evaluation. Please note that Aircraft Spruce prepaid shipping policies do not apply to COD orders. 

#### Order Fulfillment / Rates

  * **Domestic / Lower 48 Default Origin**
    * **UPS Ground:** Automated fulfilment logic evaluates contents of order, parts availability and destination to determine warehouse allocation and rate. The system will determine the warehouse with the best combination of stock, transit time, and distance and allocate as many parts from this warehouse as possible. If there are remaining items, it will consolidate to the least number of shipments. The orders will be automatically split and fulfilled from the warehouses determined as required by the system. The shopping cart and order confirmation screen will show the estimated delivery dates for each shipment that you can expect for your order. The freight charge quoted online is calculated by determining the package size(s) required to ship the order complete from the primary warehouse selected. The freight charge, if applicable, will be applied to the primary shipment, and the other shipments will invoice with no additional freight costs. When the basket contains item(s) that are not covered in our free shipping policy as additional shipments, i.e. metal, wood, oversized items, etc, the default logic will evaluate each origin as the primary warehouse and select the lowest possible cost fulfilment. This may mean that another primary warehouse selection could provide parts sooner, but the logic will provide the most economical fulfillment option. Each package will rate from the warehouse it is shipping from, and the rate in the shopping cart will be the sum of all shipments required to complete the order. Each shipment will be invoiced with the associated charge for the items on that invoice.
    * **UPS Next Day / 2-Day / 3-Day:** Default logic will evaluate the contents of the order, the destination, and the available warehouses with respect to warehouse same-day shipping cutoff times. When all warehouses are open, the system will look for the combination of most complete and closest. However, if a further warehouse is complete but the closer warehouse will require multiple shipments due to incomplete stock, the system will select the further warehouse to minimize the number of shipments and freight cost for the customer. As warehouse cutoff times pass, the system will look to get all parts from open warehouses to ship same day for soonest possible delivery. As a result, the default logic for UPS Air methods may not be the most economical, but will ensure that the parts will deliver as quickly and efficiently as possible. Each package will rate from the warehouse it is shipping from, and the rate in the shopping cart will be the sum of all shipments required to complete the order. Each shipment will be invoiced with the associated freight charge for the items on that invoice.
    * **USPS:** For USPS Priority and First Class Mail, the default logic will run through each origin as the primary warehouse and select the lowest possible cost fulfilment. This may mean that another primary warehouse selection could provide parts sooner, but the logic will look for the most economical. Each package will rate from the warehouse it is shipping from, and the rate in the shopping cart will be the sum of all shipments required to complete the order. Each shipment will be invoiced with the associated charge for the items on that invoice. Please note that USPS orders are not covered under our "Orders by 4pm Same Day Shipping"ï¿½ policy. USPS orders generally ship the following business day. Delivery dates provided are estimates, items may arrive sooner or later than displayed in the checkout. First Class Mail shipments are not trackable, allow 7-10 business days for arrival. USPS options are not offered on all orders due to carrier restrictions (i.e. Hazardous, over-weight, etc).
    * **LTL Freight:** Orders that are over the maximum weight / dimensions for UPS ground will be offered UPS LTL Freight. The default selection will choose a primary warehouse (West, Midwest, East), and import the order to that warehouse as one complete order. The shipping rate provided in the cart is for the entire order to ship from that origin warehouse. The rate provided in the cart is for the entire order to be fulfilled as one shipment from the selected origin warehouse. The order will ship when all stock is on hand at the warehouse.
  * **Warehouse Origin Override**
    * **UPS Ground:** If the user overrides the origin warehouse and chooses the primary warehouse from the list of warehouses and the items on the order are not excluded from our free shipping offer, i.e. hazardous, oversized, metal, wood, etc, the order will import to the selected warehouse as a complete order. The shipping rate provided will be the complete order from the warehouse selected. We will process the order through the warehouse selected and fill the available parts from that warehouse. Once invoiced, a backorder will generate which will be filled in the most efficient way determined. No additional freight costs will be applied to the backorders. If the basket contains items that are excluded from our free freight policy, the system will fill the parts from the selected warehouse, and use the automated logic set forth in the previous section to most efficiently fill the remaining items. The order will be automatically split and filled from the necessary warehouses. The shipping rate provided in the shopping cart will be the sum of each package / warehouse required to complete the order. The individual shipments will get the appropriate individual rates applied to them at invoicing.
    * **USPS:** The system will fill the parts from the selected warehouse, and use the automated logic set forth in the previous section to most efficiently fill the remaining items. The order will be automatically split and fill from the necessary warehouses. The shipping rate provided in the shopping cart will be the sum of each package from the warehouses required to complete the order. The individual shipments will get the appropriate individual rates applied to them at invoicing. Same USPS notes and restrictions stated in previous section apply.
    * **LTL Freight:** The Order will import to the selected warehouse with the shipping rate determined by the complete order shipping from that location. The order is set to ship complete upon import, and we will wait for complete stock before sending the order. If ship and backorder is requested, additional shipping charges will apply.
  * **Alaska**
    * When an Alaskan zip code is entered as the destination, the warehouse origin will default to our Wasilla, AK location. This local operation provides the most economical shipping rates and you will be provided with a delivery schedule for the in stock items. Items not in stock at the local branch will be transferred from other locations and fulfilled from the Alaska branch when they are received unless otherwise directed. The user also has the option in the shopping cart to select an origin warehouse in the lower 48, at which point the shipping rate provided will be for all packages required to fill the order. 
  * **International**
    * For international destinations, the system will evaluate stock at all export warehouses to determine the default selection of warehouse origin. The user can override the selection and choose a different warehouse origin. The orders are rated as complete by default, and all parts on the order are imported to the selected origin. The user can select to have the items "Ship and Backorder"ï¿½, in which case, the system will estimate the shipping for the items in stock at the selected warehouse, as well as estimate the shipping for the items not in stock as a complete second shipment. The estimates will be added together and a freight estimate provided. Please note the "Ship and Backorder"ï¿½ option will provide a freight estimate only, and actual freight will be calculated based on the packages' weight / dimensions at the time of shipping. 

#### International Shipping

Aircraft Spruce is recognized as the leading source of materials for aircraft builders, owners and pilots around the world. Over the past 50 years we have developed a family of customers in every part of the globe. Our International order department is more than happy to assist you in placing and processing your order for international shipment. Please note the following guidelines for placing an international order. You may place your order with any of our international representatives or directly with our USA, Corona facility. Correspondence should be sent in English or Spanish to expedite service.

To economize on the shipping costs, International orders are generally shipped complete unless otherwise advised by the customer. We utilize UPS, Fed-Ex and Air Parcel Post for most international shipments. Shipments by UPS and Fed-Ex are highly recommended because of the excellent traceability of the shipments. Parcel post traces are very time consuming and unreliable. We cannot be responsible for shipments made by Parcel Post. Our international department also utilizes the services of many other air and sea carriers. Should the services of a freight forwarder be necessary we can work with one who is familiar with our service or with one of your choice to meet all your shipment requirements.

All freight, duty and customs charges are the responsibility of the customer. If Aircraft Spruce is billed these charges on your behalf, you agree that you will be billed by Aircraft Spruce for these charges.

#### Carriers Shipping Cutoff Times

    * UPS orders will need to be placed before 4:00 pm EST and 4:00 pm PST Monday-Friday to ship out the same business day. [Click here](https://wwwapps.ups.com/ctc) to visit the UPS website for the most up-to-date transit time information. 

    * FedEx Priority & Economy orders will need to be placed before 3:00 pm EST and 1:00 pm PST Monday-Friday to ship out the same business day. FedEx Ground orders will need to be placed before 3:00 pm EST and 1:00 pm PST Monday-Friday to ship out the same business day. 

    * Most USPS Priority Mail & 1st Class placed before 11:00 am local time Monday-Friday at the origin warehouse will ship out the same business day. USPS orders are not covered under our same day shipping program so we cannot guarantee this cutoff time for same day shipping. Order placed after cutoff will be picked up by USPS on the next business day. We will use the flat rate box service if your parts fit in the box and the service cost is less than USPS Priority Mail. No tracking is available on First Class Mail. Allow 7-10 business days for delivery on First Class mail orders. 

## PAYMENT INFORMATION

#### Credit / Debit Cards

Aircraft Spruce accepts all major credit cards including Visa, Mastercard, American Express, and Discover. We do not accept Diner's Club. Online orders must be completed on one credit card, however split credit card payments are accepted on phone (877-477-7823), email (Click Here), or will call orders at any location.

We prefer first time orders to ship to the same address as the credit card billing address. If the order is routed to management for approval, we will verify the address with the customer's bank. The billing address must match exactly before the order can be processed for shipment. Additional forms of identification may be requested in order to verify legitimacy of the order. If we cannot confirm validity of card holder, we may request a wire transfer to complete the sale.

If the customer requests to ship to another address, we will first verify the billing address. If this address is correct, we will verify that the shipping address is also on file with the bank. If it is not, we request that the customer call his bank and advise them to add the alternate address to his file for verification. The customer will then notify us the address is on file with the bank. We will then call the bank and confirm. Once confirmed, the order will be released to ship. We may also, at our discretion, attempt to contact the cardholder by phone to confirm the order. If the alternate address is a hotel, we reserve the right to decline shipment until payment is received in full in advance and we confirm the customer name is registered with the hotel. We reserve the right to insist that any first time order ship to a verified billing address only.

We reserve the right to request an authorization on your credit card for the amount of the order at the time of order. When the order ships, we will settle and collect the amount of the order including but not limited to the merchandise, applicable taxes, freight, and/or ancillary charges and any authorized amounts in excess of the settled amount will be released. If your order is not able to ship before the authorization expires, you agree to allow us to settle that authorization to hold the parts for you until the order is ready for shipment. You agree to hold Aircraft Spruce harmless for any costs you incur due to over limit or insufficient funds as assessed by your credit card company or bank. Special order or dropship items are settled at the time the purchase order to our supplier is issued.

  * #### Paypal

We accept PayPal payments (via our website only) provided that the shipping address is a PayPal confirmed address. PayPal payments cannot be combined with other payment methods. Orders through PayPal cannot be modified. You must cancel the order and place a new order if necessary. The entire order amount will be settled by Paypal at the time the order is placed. If items are removed from the order, we will refund the Paypal account for the total credit due.

  * #### Cash on Delivery (COD)

Dealers and wholesale customers can order via COD but are subject to applicable UPS COD charges, additional handling ($5.00), plus regular shipping charges. Please note that Aircraft Spruce prepaid shipping policies do not apply to COD orders. 

  * #### Checks

Checks are accepted for all orders by phone (877-477-7823), email (Click Here), or at any will call location. However, checks are not accepted on web orders.

  * #### Wire Transfer

You may place an order by phone or email and pay by wire transfer. First, contact our sales staff with your parts list and destination address. They will then send you a proforma quote including all applicable charges. The banking details for sending the wire transfer will be on the proforma quote. Once we receive the funds, we will release your order for shipment.

  * #### Open Accounts (Net Terms)

Aircraft Spruce has long served many companies, schools and government agencies on an open account basis. Established companies can apply for an open account by submitting a credit application including all company data and at least three business references and bank information. Credit application forms are available on request. Open account terms are net 15 days after invoice date unless otherwise agreed upon by Aircraft Spruce.

## PRICING POLICY

#### PRICE MATCH POLICY: WILL NOT BE UNDERSOLD!

Aircraft Spruce works hard to bring you the lowest prices on every product we carry. If you have found a better price for an item at another authorized dealer, we will do everything possible to beat that price. Our Lowest Price Guaranteed is only applicable to identical conditions of sale. The item must be in stock at the other authorized dealer (not a floor sample, open box item, refurbished or demo piece). This offer applies to new purchases only.

#### GENERAL PRICING POLICY

Aircraft Spruce has always taken great pride in offering aircraft builders/owners the lowest overall prices in the industry. Many items in the catalog now show discounts for various quantity purchases. Special quotations on other quantity purchases gladly furnished on request. Our online catalog pricing is updated daily and should reflect current pricing. Should there be any kind of price discrepancy we will notify you immediately. We will continue to do our best to minimize increases and offer all our products at the best possible prices. All prices are subject to change without notice.

#### PRICING UPDATES

Although we update pricing for the online catalog daily, occasionally there may be a price discrepancy between the price online and the actual current price. If there is a price discrepancy, that we identify at the time we process the order, we will notify you by email so that you are aware of any changes. There may be a variety of reasons for this. 

## RETURN POLICY

Contact Aircraft Spruce Customer Service for RMA Number before returning any product. Call 800-861-3192 or send a message by clicking here.

Merchandise may be returned for credit or refund within 30 days from date of receipt if it returned in new, resalable condition - packed in original manufacturer's box, complete with instructions and all components (if applicable). Items that are installed or used are not eligible for return so it is the customer's responsibility to verify application eligibility prior to starting the install. Aircraft Spruce is not responsible for parts installed incorrectly due to suggested applicability. It is the duty of the purchaser / installer to verify eligibility prior to install. Any refund for a return outside of 30 days may be subject to house account credit only. Do not mail purchase information in letter form under separate cover. A restocking charge may apply on items that are missing components, are considered non-stocking parts, are outside of the 30 day return period, etc. Do not return any products C.O.D. as it cannot be accepted by our warehouse. Certain items may not be eligible for return (e.g. books, DVD's, videos, tools, special order items, cut materials, etc). The outbound freight charge for returns on items shipped under our Free Shipping promotion will be deducted from the refund. Call first for return authorization and instructions.

Important Note Regarding Canadian Returns: Returns for orders made from our Canadian facility may be returned to the Canadian warehouse. Canada returns do NOT need to go directly to either USA facility.

#### Product Warranties

In cooperation with the manufacturers we represent, Aircraft Spruce Co. warrants for a period of one year (on most products) from the date of original purchase its products to be free from defects in material and workmanship. Aircraft Spruce Co.'s obligation under this warranty is limited to repair or replacement of the purchased product only, and under no circumstances shall Aircraft Spruce Co. be liable for any loss, damage, injury, cost of repair or consequential damages of any kind in connection with the sale, use or repair of any product purchased from Aircraft Spruce Co. Products sold are subject to manufacturer's warranty policy. Defective merchandise or out of box failure of product is repaired or replaced according to each manufacturer's policy. Avionics, electrical, instruments or similar products that are defective are subject to manufacturer's warranty only and will not be replaced immediately from Aircraft Spruce inventory. Out of box failures will not always be replaced at no charge. In some cases, we require that a new item be purchased and the defective unit be sent to the manufacturer for evaluation. Once the manufacturer agrees to replace the product for Aircraft Spruce, we will refund the initial unit charge.

#### Damaged or Shorted Merchandise

Each parcel carriers $100.00 insurance against loss or damage. Additional insurance coverage will be added as required per parcel. Open and examine all packages promptly. Notify the Aircraft Spruce Customer Service Department of any discrepancies in the order. If the merchandise is received in damaged condition or the carrier fails to deliver the entire shipment as shown on the Bill of Lading covering motor freight delivery, make note of the damage or shortage on the Bill of Lading and ask the driver to sign it. Then call the terminal office of the carrier and institute a claim for the loss or damage. If a package delivered by UPS arrives damaged, report this to the driver immediately. UPS will issue a report on the damage to Aircraft Spruce at which time a replacement shipment can be made.

## PRIVACY POLICY

This privacy statement covers the site www.aircraftspruce.com owned and operated by Aircraft Spruce Co. 

#### This privacy statement explains

  * What personally identifiable information Aircraft Spruce collects.
  * What personally identifiable information third parties collect through the Web site.
  * What organization collects the information.
  * How Aircraft Spruce Co. uses the information.
  * With whom Aircraft Spruce Co. may share user information.
  * What choices are available to users regarding collection, use and distribution of the information.
  * What types of security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under Aircraft Spruce Co. control.
  * How users can correct any inaccuracies in the information.
  * If users have questions or concerns regarding this statement, they should first contact Aircraft Spruce Co. in writing to the Website Information department, PO Box 4000, Corona, CA 92880.

#### Information Collection and Use Information Collection

Aircraft Spruce Co. is the sole owner of the information collected on www.aircraftspruce.com. Aircraft Spruce collects information from our users at several different points on our Web site.

#### Registration

The use of this website is not limited to registered users. A user may register with the website in order to view order history, order details, subscribe to newsletters, request returns, etc. During registration a user is required to give contact information (such as name and email address). We use this information to contact the user about services on our site for which he has expressed interest. Address and contact information will be used to provide service throughout the order and fulfillment process. 

#### Order

We request information from the user on our order form. A user must provide contact information (such as name, email, and shipping address) and financial information (such as credit card number, expiration date). This information is used for billing purposes and to fill customer's orders. If we have trouble processing an order, the information is used to contact the user. We may use the information to verify the legitimacy of an order by contacting the customer's bank.

#### Information Use

Personal information such as email addresses, physical addresses and financial information are not disclosed to any third parties. This information is used exclusively by Aircraft Spruce Co. The company may decide to use and communicate purchasing history and consumer behavior to third parties, but only in aggregate form, rendering personal identification impossible. Information about other parties

If you request that your Aircraft Spruce purchase be shipped to someone other than yourself (such as a gift recipient), we use the information you provide about the other person to fulfill the shipment.

#### Profile

We store information that we collect through cookies, log files, pixels, and/or third parties to create a profile of our users. A profile is stored information that we keep on individual users that details their viewing preferences. Consequently, collected information is tied to the users personally identifiable information to provide offers and improve the content of the site for the user. This profile is used to tailor a user's visit to our Web site, and to direct pertinent marketing promotions to them. We do not share your personal profile with other third parties. Items from your profile may be shared in aggregate form only.

#### Cookies

A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's computer tied to information about the user. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. For the session ID cookie, once users close the browser, the cookie simply terminates. A persistent cookie is a small text file stored on the user's hard drive for an extended period of time. Persistent cookies can be removed by following Internet browser help file directions.

By setting a cookie on our site, users would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on our site. If users reject the use of cookies, certain elements of the web site may cease to function, such as adding items to the Shopping Cart.

Some of our business partners use cookies on our site (for example, Google Analytics, Google Ads, etc). However, we have no access to or control over these cookies, once we have given permission for them to set cookies for advertising. Information regarding the privacy policies of third parties can be provided. Please contact our webmaster for details.

This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by Aircraft Spruce Co. only and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

#### Log Files

Like most standard Web site servers we use log files. This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track users movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to personally identifiable information.

Pixels can "work with" existing cookies on a computer if they are both from the same Web site or advertising company. That means, for example, that if a person visited www.companyX.com, which uses an advertising company's clear gif, the Web site would match the pixel identifier and the advertising company's cookie ID number, to show the past online behavior for that computer. This collected information would then be given to the advertising company or Web site.

In addition, we use pixels in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by the recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. If users would like to opt-out of these emails, please see the Opt-out section.

### Communications From The Site

#### Special Offers and Updates

We send all new members a welcoming email to verify password and username. Established members will occasionally receive information on products, services, special deals, and a newsletter if they have opted in to receiving these materials. Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option to not receive these types of communications. Please see the Choice and Opt-out sections. Newsletter

If a user wishes to subscribe to our newsletter, we ask for contact information such as name and email address. Out of respect for our users privacy we provide a way to opt-out of these communications. Please see the Choice and Opt-out sections.

#### Service Announcements

On rare occasions it is necessary to send out a strictly service related announcement. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance we might send users an email. Generally, users may not opt-out of these communications, though they can deactivate their account. However, these communications are not promotional in nature.

#### Customer Service

We communicate with users on a regular basis to provide requested services and in regards to issues relating to their account we reply via email or phone, in accordance with the users wishes. Sharing Legal Disclaimer

Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on our Web site.

#### Aggregate Information (non-personally identifiable)

We may share aggregated demographic information with our partners and advertisers. For example, we may decide to share, the aggregate number of customers Aircraft Spruce Co. by zip code. This is not linked to any personally identifiable information.

These are the instances in which we will share users' personal information:

We DO NOT Share Personal Information with Third Parties

#### Third Party Intermediaries

We use an outside shipping company to ship orders, and a credit card processing company to bill users for goods and services. These companies do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes.

#### Service Providers

We may partner with other third parties to provide specific services. When the user signs up for these particular services, we share names, or other contact information that is necessary for the third party to provide these services. These third parties are not allowed to use personally identifiable information except for the purpose of providing these services.

#### Business Transitions

In the event Aircraft Spruce Co. goes through a business transition, such as a merger, being acquired by another company, or selling a portion of its assets, user's personal information will, in most instances, be part of the assets transferred.

#### Choice/Opt-out

Our users are given the opportunity to opt-out of having their information used for purposes not directly related to our site at the point where we ask for information. For example, our order form has an opt-out mechanism so users who buy a product from us, but don't want any marketing material, can keep their email address off our lists. Users who no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications may opt-out of receiving these communications by replying to unsubscribe in the subject line in the email or email us. We also offer an opt-out mechanism on the MY ACCOUNT PAGE.

#### Links

This Web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we, Aircraft Spruce Co., are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site.

#### Surveys & Contests

From time-to-time our site requests information from users via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code). Contact information will be used to notify the winners and award prizes. Anonymous Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site. Users personally identifiable information is not shared with third parties unless we give prior notice and choice. Though we may use an intermediary to conduct these surveys or contests, they may not use user's personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes.

#### Chat Rooms, Message Boards, and Public Forums

Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online - for example on message boards, through e-mail, or in chat areas - that information can be collected and used by others. In short, by posting personal information online that is publicly accessible, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return.

#### Security

This Web site takes every precaution to protect our users' information. When users submit sensitive information via the Web site, their information is protected both online and off-line. When our registration/order form asks users to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number), that information is encrypted and is protected with the best encryption software in the industry - SSL. We are also PCI compliant. While on a secure page, such as our order form, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when users are just surfing.

While we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also do everything in our power to protect user-information off-line. All of our user's information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our billing clerk or a customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information. Our employees must use password-protected screen-savers when they leave their desk. When they return, they must re-enter their password to re-gain access to user information. Furthermore, ALL employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices. Every quarter, as well as any time new policies are added, our employees are notified and/or reminded about the importance we place on privacy, and what they can do to ensure our user's information is protected. Finally, the servers that store personally identifiable information are in a secure environment, in a locked facility.

If users have any questions about the security at our Web site, users can contact us by clicking here .

#### Correcting/Updating/Deleting/Deactivating Personal Information

If a users personally identifiable information changes (such as zip code, phone, email or postal address), or if a user no longer desires our service, we provide a way to correct, update or delete/deactivate user's personally identifiable information. To request this, please contact us by clicking here.

#### Notification of Changes

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

If, however, we are going to use user's personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify users via email and by posting a notice on our Web site for 30 days.

#### Children's Privacy

The Services are intended for general audiences and not for children under the age of 13. If we become aware that we have collected 'personal information' (as defined by the United States Children's Online Privacy Protection Act) from children under the age of 13 without legally-valid parental consent, we will take reasonable steps to delete it as soon as possible. We do not knowingly process data of EU residents under the age of 16 without parental consent. If we become aware that we have collected data from an EU resident under the age of 16 without parental consent, we will take reasonable steps to delete it as soon as possible. We also comply with other age restrictions and requirements in accordance with applicable local laws.

#### California Privacy Rights

California law gives residents of California the right under certain circumstances to request information from us regarding the manner in which we share certain categories of personal information (as defined by applicable California law) with third parties for their direct marketing purposes. However, Aircraft Spruce does not share your personal information with third parties for their own direct marketing purposes.

#### Data Security

Aircraft Spruce, as developer and manager of the Aircraft Spruce portal has taken the necessary steps to safeguard the integrity of its data and prevent unauthorized access to information that is maintained in our computer systems. These measures are designed and intended to prevent corruption of data, block unknown or unauthorized access to our systems and information, ensure the integrity of information that is transmitted between our customers and Aircraft Spruce, and to provide reasonable protection of private information that is in our possession. 

For security purposes and to make sure this service remains available to all users, Aircraft Spruce uses special software programs for monitoring and auditing network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise to cause damage to this computer system. Aircraft Spruce also uses proprietary software tools to control access to specific applications and services and industry standard security software to protect data that is transmitted electronically between users and the Aircraft Spruce website. 

**WARNING** \-- If security monitoring reveals possible evidence of criminal activity, information pertaining to such activity may be provided to law enforcement officials. Unauthorized attempts to upload information and/or change information on the Aircraft Spruce website are strictly prohibited and are subject to prosecution under the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986 and Title 18 U.S.C. Sec.1001 and 1030. 

The information contained in this policy statement should not be construed in any way as giving business, legal, or other advice, or warranting as fail proof, the security of information provided via the Aircraft Spruce Website. 

#### Contact Information

If users have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us by clicking here br> Aircraft Spruce Co.  
PO Box 4000  
Corona, CA 92880  
Last Edited on 2018-05-25  

## INTERNATIONAL ORDERS

Aircraft Spruce is recognized as the leading source of materials for aircraft builders, owners and pilots around the world. For more than 50 years, we have developed a family of customers in every part of the globe. Our International order department is more than happy to assist you in placing and processing your order for international shipment. Please note the following guidelines for placing an international order. You may place your order with any of our international representatives or directly through our website or international sales department. Correspondence should be sent in English or Spanish to expedite service.

Requests for quotation are processed within 72 hours, unless additional research is required on a product. All prices quoted and invoiced by Aircraft Spruce West are FOB Corona, CA and by Aircraft Spruce East are FOB, Peachtree City, GA. A quotation is processed as a proforma invoice for all overseas customers. A proforma invoice is not considered an order until funds are received to process the order. Actual freight charges may differ from a freight quote or estimate provided by a freight carrier. 

First time orders are preferably received by fax, e-mail, or website to insure correct notation of name and billing and shipping information. Please note the information on 8130 forms in the following paragraphs. If 8130 forms are required, we must be notified at the time the order is placed so that we may special order the documentation.

To economize on the shipping costs, International orders are generally shipped complete unless otherwise advised by the customer. We utilize DHL, UPS, Fed-Ex and Air Parcel Post for most international shipments. Shipments by DHL, UPS and Fed-Ex are highly recommended because of the excellent traceability of the shipments. Parcel post traces are very time consuming and unreliable. We cannot be responsible for shipments made by USPS Parcel Post. Our international department also utilizes the services of many other air and sea carriers. Should the services of a freight forwarder be necessary we can work with one who is familiar with our service or with one of your choice to meet your shipment requirements. 

<4>All freight, duty and customs charges are the responsibility of the customer.

Preferred methods of payment are credit cards (American Express, Visa, Mastercard, Discover) and by bank transfer. There is an additional $20 service charge for bank transfers. When making a bank transfer please fax a copy of your transfer along with your order request to ensure accurate allocation of funds. Please note that if payment is made by bank transfer there is an approximate 7 day delay before funds are confirmed and allocated. 

A complete listing of Aircraft Spruce international representatives can be found by clicking here. Always remember to furnish your complete communications information on your correspondence so that we may respond to your requests promptly. We welcome your orders and look forward to being part of your team during your entire project. 

**HAZMAT SHIPMENTS:** A fee is charged on all international shipments containing hazardous materials. This fee covers special packaging, documentation, and certification requirements that apply to hazmat orders shipping to customers outside the United States. 

## QUALITY CONTROL

Aircraft Spruce Co. is a U.S. based aircraft parts distribution company which provides a full line of certificated and experimental aircraft parts, avionics, and pilot supplies to retail and wholesale customers worldwide. Aircraft Spruce was established in 1965 and maintains distribution facilities in Corona, CA, Peachtree City, GA, and Brantford, ON, Canada. Aircraft Spruce is solely a distributor of aircraft parts and does not manufacture, engineer, or repair aviation products, and as such, we do not require national authority approval. Aircraft Spruce is an authorized distributor for most major aircraft parts manufacturers, and a full product line can be found in our 1000+ page parts catalog and on our website.

Aircraft Spruce has approximately 200 employees and operates using standard quality control procedures applicable to parts distribution. The distribution facilities in Corona, CA and Peachtree City, GA are 61,000 square feet each and the facility in Brantford, ON is 20,000 square feet. All facilities are modern, well lit, and equipped with the latest communication and computer technology throughout. All warehouses are furnished with the modern metal racking and shelving, with dedicated areas for efficient receiving, inspection, and labeling of incoming products to maintain total traceability from dock to stock to shipping. 

Certified parts are only sourced through approved manufacturers or distributors and flow requirements include the following counterfeit/unapproved parts clause 8.1.4: To prevent the use of counterfeit parts, Aircraft Spruce utilizes the following processes. 

  * An approved supplier list is maintained to ensure product can meet requirements of our customer and Aircraft Spruce terms of purchase.
  * A statement for each supplier to not knowingly supply counterfeit parts is included in our terms of purchase provided with the purchase orders. 
  * General requirements for items purchased include certifications of conformity from manufacturer. 
  * When available or applicable, full test reports including material certifications are required on purchased products. 
  * During inspection/verification, trained employees review characteristics as well as all documentation relating to the product for accuracy and authenticity. 
  * A documented process for the updating of prints and specifications prevents the use of obsolete specifications and or prints. 
  * A documented process is used for the control of nonconforming product including segregation to avoid unintended use. 
  * Strict lot control is utilized for all incoming material, storage and outgoing shipments.

Any counterfeit/unapproved discovered will be segregated for return and subject to reporting to the appropriate entities (GIDEP, etc.).

## OTHER CONDITIONS OF SALE

#### Ship and Backorder 

Our default shipping option will allow us to ship all in stock products to you immediately from the nearest geographic warehouse with inventory and backorder any items which are not in stock. The items that did not ship will be sent from the next closest warehouse with inventory. If we do not have any inventory of the product, we will ship the parts as soon as any warehouse receives stock from our suppliers. Aircraft Spruce pays the freight on most backorder shipments within the lower 48 states (except oversize packages, hazardous products, and products which would have required a separate package if shipped with the first shipment). Unless otherwise instructed, we will Ship and Backorder (if necessary) to insure prompt delivery of all in stock items. 

#### Hold and Ship Complete

This shipping option instructs us to hold your entire order until all items are in stock. You authorize us to charge your credit card for the entire amount of the order to secure those parts for you in advance, even if the order cannot ship the same day due to backordered items. This will allow for all items on your order to ship at one time, but it can also cause indefinite delays in shipment if any items are not in stock and delivery from our suppliers is delayed. We do not recommend this option except for certain export orders or orders where the products not in stock are oversize or hazardous, which would require additional shipping charges if backordered and shipped later. If the only products missing are small and can be shipped by mail, we will backorder them and ship all in stock items immediately. Please request this in the Special Instructions box in the Shopping Cart if you prefer this option.

#### Certificate of Conformance and Form 8130 (Export)

Aircraft Spruce provides you with its own Certificate of Conformance for our products at no charge. This is noted on every invoice. Factory certification and test reports are available on some items and 8130 Forms are available on FAA approved products. A cost of $15 per product on manufacturer certs and $50 per product on 8130 forms is charged to secure these forms. Please inquire at time of order if test reports/8130 Forms are available for the items you are ordering. If available, the forms must be requested at time of order and in some cases the product must be special-ordered from the factory with the forms. These forms cannot be furnished after you receive the product. Anticipate shipping delays if 8130 Forms are requested. If you require these forms, you can request that the salesperson add them to your order. If you are ordering online, you can check off which form you require for each item in your cart. The system will automatically add the $15 or $50 charge to your bill. Due to delays and costs involved in furnishing these forms, we strongly suggest that you check to see if the Aircraft Spruce Certificate of Conformance will be acceptable in lieu of Form 8130. 

#### Cutting Charges

Certain orders for cut materials (i.e. wood, metal, etc) may incur an additional cutting charge. Nearly all our cut material orders are shipped with no additional charges, however, should your order warrant a cutting charge, you will be contacted with an explanation and request for approval. If approved, we will proceed with the order and if it is not approved we will provide alternative solutions. 

#### ADDING ON TO AN ORDER

In order to ensure efficient, accurate processing of orders in the warehouse, we have several restrictions for adding on to placed orders. The restrictions include: 

  * Orders that have "Packed" or "Invoiced" status 
  * Orders qualifying for free shipping 
  * Orders placed by PayPal 
  * Orders containing special order items 

We have also implemented a 1:00 pm local time cutoff for add-ons at the respective origin warehouse on the day the order is shipping. If the order has an "open" status and it is before the 1:00 pm cutoff, you can add on to it using the website or by calling our Customer Service department. If we cannot add products to the open order due to the restrictions listed above, we will be glad to take a new order for the additional products. 

#### OUR 100% RECYCLED, BIODEGRADABLE PACKING PAPER

Aircraft Spruce has used biodegradable corn starch packing peanuts to pack outgoing orders for a number of years which provided excellent protection of the products in the box, but could also cause a mess when the box was opened and unpacked. We have looked for a more customer friendly packing material alternative for some time, and we are pleased to announce that we are now using a 100% recycled, 100% biodegradable paper packing material to replace the peanuts. This material is suitable to our high volume shipping requirements, protects the contents of the box as well as the peanuts, and will allow customers to unpack their shipments without having to pick up peanuts afterward. 

#### INVOICE / ORDERS PAID BY CHECK

For our customer's convenience we enclose a copy of the invoice covering the order with each order shipped except those shipped to a third party. If the order is paid by check and the check did not cover the full amount of the invoice, the amount of underpayment will be sent C.O.D. for the balance due plus C.O.D. fee of $10.50 rather than delay the order. If you have overpaid by check, the overpayment will be credited to your account or refunded. C.O.D. shipments are considered paid as soon as we receive payment from UPS, and credit card orders are paid automatically at time of shipment. 

#### WHEN YOU RECEIVE YOUR ORDER

Upon receipt, the package should be opened promptly and material checked against the packing slip enclosed. Items out-of-stock at time of shipment will be marked as back-ordered to follow.' These items will not be charged on the invoice enclosed with the package and will be forwarded as soon as delivery is received from our suppliers. The backordered items will not be charged until shipped. About 90% of the items featured in our catalog are carried in stock. Special items of hardware, bearings, unusual fittings and slow moving items are special ordered as required. However, even with the large inventory we carry, it is not uncommon to come up short on some items. If an item is missing and not marked backordered, please advise us immediately.

#### BACKORDERS

Backorder are shipped from the warehouse that receives stock first. Although we make every effort to ship all orders complete, it is often necessary to backorder one or more items if we are out of stock. When the partial order is shipped and invoiced, you are not charged for the backordered item(s) until these items are shipped. You are billed only for what is shipped. A backorder is created and shipped as soon as the items arrive. The backorder is then invoiced and any overpayment from the first invoice is applied to it. If you do not wish to have any items backordered, or wish to cancel an existing backorder, just let us know. We will do so immediately if the backorder has not been shipped. We are working continuously to keep all items in stock to preclude backorders. If a backorder is necessary, we do appreciate your patience. Aircraft Spruce pays the shipping costs within the 48 contiguous United States by surface shipping on backorders when the backordered items could have been shipped via UPS inside the first package at no additional freight cost. Except when the backordered items are oversize, hazardous, contain one gallon or larger, or COD shipments. We will continue to strive to maintain stock of all our products to keep the necessity for backordering parts to a minimum.

#### AMAZON RESELLERS / PROCESSING FEES

Any customer that is inputting orders obtained from other websites, ie Amazon.com, and processing them through Aircraft Spruce is subject to an additional charge per item for handling, packaging, marketing, et al. Free shipping offers may be voided on orders obtained from other selling channels. All accounts can be suspended without notice if the account experiences high volumes of customer service issues.

#### OPEN ACCOUNT

Aircraft Spruce has long served many companies, schools and government agencies on an open account basis. Established companies can apply for an open account by submitting a credit application including all company data and at least three business references and bank information. Credit application forms available on request. Open account terms are net 15 days after invoice date.

#### DEALER / OEM / WHOLESALE DISCOUNTS

We have offered discounts to our regular dealers and FBO's for many years for resale purposes, and we welcome the addition of new dealers to best serve aviation consumers worldwide. Due to the very competitive and low margin nature of most of the prices shown in this catalog, all discounts are based on volume purchasing. Discounts for many items are shown below the product in the catalog. Discounts for items with discounts not shown in the catalog or for larger quantities than those listed can be quoted by mail, phone, or FAX upon request. You can be assured, as an aviation dealer, that you will receive the best possible net prices from Aircraft Spruce on all product lines that we carry. If you ever find a lower current advertised price on any product, just let us know and we'll beat it. Call for an Aircraft Spruce dealer application if interested in becoming a dealer of Aircraft Spruce.

#### SPECIAL ORDER ITEMS

Over the years, one of the services that our company offers that seems to be most appreciated by our customers is our willingness to research and provide quotations for special items. Other supply firms tend to discourage special requests due to the time and effort it takes to find these items, and request that customers order catalog items only. We have always taken a different approach and welcome requests for non-catalog items. Call or write and provide as much information as possible including make, model, serial number of aircraft and exact part number or product you need, plus your credit card number. Within 24 hours if possible, we will advise you of the price and delivery time on the item, at which time you can place your order if acceptable. Once an order is placed for a special order item, it cannot be cancelled or returned and must be paid in advance. If we cannot drop ship your special order, then freight charges from the factory to our warehouse will be added to your invoice. Our goal is to provide you with everything you need - if you do not find it in this catalog, let us know and we'll find it for you!

#### NON-STOCKING ITEMS

Non-stocking products from Aircraft Spruce are products that we do not carry in our warehouses and must be specially ordered. It is the customer's responsibility to determine that the product is correct for their own application. By purchasing non-stocking products, the customer is agreeing to pay any cancellation or restocking fee assessed by the manufacturer or supplier should the customer wish to cancel or return the item. Additional inbound freight may also apply to get non-stocking products from the manufacturer to our warehouse if a direct dropship is not an option. Some items may be non-cancellable / non-returnable once ordered. We suggest contacting a sales agent for lead time details prior to placing the order to ensure we can meet your delivery schedule. By submitting the order for a non-stocking product, you are agreeing to these terms and conditions. Please call our sales staff for any additional questions or concerns.

#### WAIVER OF LIABILITY AND INDEMNIFICATION AGREEMENT

Inasmuch as Aircraft Spruce Co. has no opportunity to supervise the manufacture, installation or maintenance of the parts supplied by it, nor any opportunity to participate in the design or manufacture of the various certificated and homebuilt aircraft in which its parts are utilized, the purchaser by placing an order and accepting said merchandise from Aircraft Spruce Co. agrees that all materials purchased will be used solely at purchaser's risk and that purchaser will indemnify and hold Aircraft Spruce Co., its owners and employees, free and harmless from all loss, liability or damage resulting from claims brought by any reason of any alleged failure or defect of any part or parts supplied by Aircraft Spruce Co.

#### WILLCALL

If you choose to pick your order up in one of our stores, you must present your method of payment at time of pickup. If paying by credit card, please bring your credit card with you to the store. We do not allow prepayment by credit and pick up of parts of the counter. If you will be using a runner, we recommend applying for a net account. We do not accept checks at the Will Call store. Saturday Paint Mixing: Mixed paints must be ordered in advance for will call pick up on Saturdays. We cannot mix paint on Saturdays.
